Guide to the Alfred C. Burrill Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Alfred C. Burrill papers
1900-1903
MS 1657
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers consist of letters, photographs, postcards, and clippings, which document Alfred C. Burrill's summer of 1903, when he was a student at Yale's summer school of forestry in Pennsylvania. Burrill's work on a study of poplar trees, which was conducted in Maine later in that summer, is also described in these papers, as are a few student essays from 1900.
Burrill, Alfred C.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from David McCord's Trolley Stop, 1988.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Alfred C. Burrill Papers consist of letters, photographs, postcards, and clippings, which document Alfred C. Burrill's summer of 1903, when he was a student at Yale's summer school of forestry in Pennsylvania. Burrill's work on a study of poplar trees, which was conducted in Maine later that summer, is also described in these papers. The papers also include a few student essays from 1900. The papers were purchased from David McCord's Trolley Stop in 1988.
The materials in these papers were originally mounted in a scrapbook, which has now been disbound. Previously concealed documents on the backs of photographs and postcards add depth to the information conveyed in Burrill's long, detailed letters home. It is obvious from the table of contents pages that Burrill had originally included additional letters in this scrapbook which described his student life at Harvard University during the spring of 1903. These letters were apparently removed by the dealer before the scrapbook was sold to Yale.
Forests and forestry; Lumbering; Photographs; Postcards; Burrill, Alfred C.; Yale University. School of Forestry
- Inventory
  - Biographical material, table of contents pages, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters 4-5, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters 6-7, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters 8-9, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters 10-14, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: camp, paper mill, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: trees from Maine study, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Postcards, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Printed material, memorabilia, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Writings, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 10)